# **Gabriel Mansford-Martino**

Cairns, Queensland | Phone: +61 7 439 515 439 | Email: gabriel.p.martino@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/gabrielmartino1 | UX/UI Portfolio: www.gabrielmm.com.au

### SUMMARY

Possessing excellent organisational skills and a meticulous eye for detail, I have successfully managed multiple projects, meeting strict deadlines and ensuring compliance with project requirements. With over five years of experience in architectural drafting and project coordination, I have developed strong communication, interpersonal and problem-solving skills, enabling me to work effectively with a range of stakeholders including project managers, clients, and contractors. I am committed to continuous learning and growth and am excited about the opportunity to leverage my skills and experience to contribute to the success of a new team.

## PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Cairns Hospital Cardiac Catheter Lab
- Cairns Hospital Hybrid Theatre & Operating Theatre
- Mareeba Hospital Radiology Extension
- Mareeba Department of Agriculture and Fisheries (DAF)
- Cooktown Emergency Department
- Reef Hotel Casino Entry & Gaming Refurbishment
- Cairns Airport Domestic Terminal
- ADF Lavarack Barracks
- ADF HMAS Cairns

### Throughout these projects and many more I have consistently delivered:

- Project Submissions and presentations that have successfully impressed the likes of Cairns Airport and the Reef Hotel Casino.
- Provided accurate pricing and timelines for tender submissions.
- Developed project briefs and design requirements through liaising with clients, stakeholders, user groups and government bodies.
- Developed concept drawings, schematic design, detail design, construction documentation, specifications and finishes schedules.
- Coordinated engineers, contractors and relevant authorities during the schematic and detail design, and construction documentation stages.
- Reviewed and scored builders tender submissions.
- Mitigated health and safety and financial risks in the design and construction process; including site inspections, and designing to ASNZ standards.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# Senior Draftsman / Design coordinator / IT Manager 8 Pencils PTY LTD / MMP Architects

2017 - Present Cairns, QLD

Architectural drafting using Revit, producing highly detailed BIM models, construction documentation & large scale concepts to assist in the building & design process. Throughout the course of a project, I conduct interviews with stakeholders and clients, run design coordination meetings with consultants, develop design briefs and achieve client sign off at key project points.

Tools Used: Revit, Autocad, Unreal Engine, Lumion, Photoshop, InDesign, Microsoft Suite, Google Suite Key Accomplishments:

- Experience working with building certifiers and relevant authorities to obtain verification approvals.
- Worked within a team between 5 10 people, coordinating with clients, engineers, contractors and relevant authorities.
- Extensive experience in architectural visualisations using Unreal Engine and Lumion for concepts, simulations, and presentations.
- Developed comprehensive construction documentation to Australian standards and project specific guidelines.
- Mitigated health and safety and financial risks in the design and construction process, including site inspections, and designing to ASNZ standards.

# UX/UI Designer AML Cloud | www.amlcloud.io

2023 – Present Remote

Currently working remotely with the financial tech start-up AML Cloud to develop a streamlined and consolidated platform for users to track transactions, set rule parameters, screen customers and sanction screening to combat financial crime.

Tools Used: Figma, FigJam, Miro, Adobe Suite, GitHub, Chat GPT, Microsoft Suite, Google Suite Key Accomplishments:

- Onboarded and vetted subject matter experts in sanction screening.
- Interviewed users and experts to extract the key insights to define the requirements of software.
- Working with 10+ software engineers including backend, front end and Al.
- Developing product brochures for sales teams.

## Company Director Virtual Spark

2016 – 2017 Brisbane, QLD

Virtual reality simulations for the construction industry using a business to business model. This helped clients to become fully immersed in their project to visualise and understand the design process and outcomes. Tools Used: Unreal Engine, Revit, Unity, Maya, 3DS Max, Premiere Pro, Photoshop.

**Key Accomplishments:** 

- Created high quality architectural visualisations and walkthroughs using virtual reality as a platform.
- Presented finished works to clients & stakeholders.
- Conducted research and development to further the businesses service capabilities.

# **Quality Assurance Testing / Graphic Artist InTouch Softworks**

2014 – 2017 Brisbane, QLD

My duties at InTouch Softworks cover a broad range of roles including; specification and design documentation, storyboarding and design, user experience testing, quality assurance testing and bug capture. The process used for QA testing involved documenting all possible user paths in an application, testing each path using multiple devices and documenting bugs as well as replication methods and style inconsistencies. This broad range of tasks allows me to be useful at all levels of the development stage of applications and other softwares. Key Accomplishments:

- Coordinated software development team of 5 people.
- Executed bug capture, replication and documentation.
- Produced product specification and design documentation
- Storyboarding
- User experience design & testing

### **EDUCATION**

### Certificate in UX/UI | 2022 | Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria (Remote)

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to User Experience & User Interface Design. Skills learned consist of HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, User-Centric Design Research, Visual Prototyping and Wireframing, User Interface Development.

Bachelor of Games and Interactive Entertainment | 2010 - 2013 | Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Queensland

The 3 year course focused on building skills in game design, game research, interaction design, level design, animation, prototyping & project management.

Certificate IV Small Business Management | 2015 | **Mission Australia - New Enterprise Incentive Scheme**The NEIS program assisted in developing realistic business plans, learning fundamental business processes and putting them into practice and managing cash flow.

### REFERENCES

#### Michael Martino | 8 Pencils/MMP Architects

Director 0407 337 793 michael@8pencils.com.au

#### Deborah Spalding | Cairns and Hinterland Hospital and Health Service

BOHS, Project Officer, Capital Projects 0428 688 192 Deborah.spalding@health.qld.gov.au

#### Kevin Anderson | Hutchinson Builders

Project Manager 0419 762 441 Kevin.Anderson@hutchies.com.au